The Captain is a comedy, drama film directed by Nash Edgerton.
A hungover plane captain wakes up to discover he's done a very bad thing.
The Captain, played by Taika Waititi.
The Dead Passenger, played by Nash Edgerton.
Dead Body, played by David Michôd.
Dead Body, played by Joel Edgerton.
Dead Body, played by Andy Bate.
Captain Phillips is a 2013 American biographical
action-thriller film directed by Paul Greengrass.
Based on the 2009 Maersk Alabama hijacking, the film tells the story of Captain Richard
Phillips, an American merchant mariner who was taken hostage by Somali pirates.
It stars Tom Hanks as Phillips, alongside Barkhad
Abdi as pirate leader Abduwali Muse.
The screenplay by Billy Ray is based on Phillips's 2010 book A Captain's Duty: Somali Pirates,
Navy SEALs, and Dangerous Days at Sea, which Phillips co-wrote with Stephan Talty.
Scott Rudin, Dana Brunetti and Michael De Luca
served as producers on the project.
It premiered at the 2013 New York Film Festival, and was
theatrically released on October 11, 2013.
The film emerged as a critical and commercial success, receiving acclaim from
critics and grossing $218 million against a budget of $55 million.
Captain Phillips received six Academy Award nominations, including Best
Picture, Best Adapted Screenplay and Best Supporting Actor for Abdi.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.